ERI KILANOWSKI

ASPIRING FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/erikilanowski



https://github.com/eri707

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am looking to apply my strong work ethic, leadership, teamwork, and professional experience to my new career as a software developer. Though the last 10 years of my career was spent as an external auditor, over the last year I have put a significant amount of time and effort into learning new skills with personal training & mentorship from a skilled senior software engineer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming Languages

- C#
- **JavaScript**
- HTML/CSS

Technologies

- ASP.NET Core, MVC, Razor
- Node / Express
- VueJS

Tools

- Visual Studio + VS Code
- Git + Github
- Microsoft Azure

PROJECTS

Restaurant Roulette PWA App (WIP)

Vue3, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Google Cloud Platform (Firebase)

This project is internally dubbed "Restaurant Tinder" and its function is to show users restaurants which match their preference parameters until they swipe right on the one they want to visit.

Smart Home REST API

C# ASP.NET 5.0, SQL Server, Xunit Integration Tests

This REST API is a model microservice. Users can add rooms and then devices such as light bulbs, switches and sensors to said rooms. Project includes a full suite of BVT integration tests written using Xunit.

BugTracker REST API + Razor Pages

C# Asp.NET 5.0, SQL Server, In-memory cache, Razor Pages, Alpine.JS, Bulma CSS

A staple in every portfolio, this project is a REST API and a front-end written in Razor Pages. The API and the front end both use a shared repository. Front end uses Bulma CSS with some interactive components via AlpineJS.

Recipe Catalog

Vue 2.6, Node Express, JavaScript

First full-scale project written entirely in JavaScript. REST API with VueJS front-end with custom, hand-written CSS.

LEADERSHIP SKILLS SUMMARY



Time Management

I like to use to-do lists to manage and prioritize multiple tasks at once. This strategy has allowed me to stay ahead of schedule in everything I do.



Team Leadership

During busy season, team motivation decreased due to fatigue. I always motivated and inspired them to do their best work, and then kept them on task, on schedule, and on budget.



Big Picture Thinker

Rather than focusing on the small details I put emphasis on the urgency of the problems which could have critical implications on clients' financial statements.

EXPERIENCE

Accounting Manager (05/2016 – 10/2017)

Minamiaoyama FAS Co [®] Tokyo, Japan

- Advised clients about tax law, provided review documents, identified problems and implemented solutions
- Offered accounting leadership to coworkers and improved professionalism across the company
- Managed a team of junior auditors and tax accountants

Senior Auditor (09/2014 - 12/2016)

Deloitte Japan ⁽²⁾ Tokyo, Japan

- Compiled and submitted reports on clients' financial results
- Worked with dozens of companies in varied industries building annual audit plans and implementing audit procedures
- Led the audit processes often as an on-site director
- Managed a team of junior and senior auditors.

Senior Auditor (01/2013 – 08/2014)

YUSEI Audit & Co Tokyo, Japan

- Identified issues with financial documents and reported signs of fraud to both the executives and internal company auditors
- Led small teams in each audit process as an on-site director

Senior Auditor (01/2011 – 12/2012)

CPA & Auditing Oversight Board ⁽²⁾ Tokyo, Japan

Government-run association focused on verifying the quality of auditing done by audit firms

- Verified audit firm financial reports and related paperwork
- Interacted with the audit team members to clarify audit reports

Senior Auditor (12/2005 – 12/2010)

Ernst & Young Japan (Osaka, Japan » Tokyo, Japan)

- Led teams as an on-site director performing audits of medium sized teams
- Tasks ran the usual gamut of audit-related items such as risk assessment, stock & asset

EDUCATION

Bachelors in English Language & Literature (1997 – 2001) [®] Kyoto, Japan Kyoto Women's University

CERTIFICATION

Certified Public Accountant – Japan (2009 – Now)

The Japanese Institute of Certified Public Accountants